Abhilash Shrivas

Phone: 6261088715 Email: Abhilashcyberminds@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/abhilash-shrivas-9196ba235/

Summary:

With 3 years of experience in customer support and 2.11 years specializing in IT recruitment, I offer a unique blend of skills that enhance client interactions and recruitment processes. My background in customer support has honed my ability to address and resolve client concerns effectively, ensuring a positive experience. Meanwhile, my IT recruitment experience covers the entire recruitment lifecycle, including job postings, candidate searches, interviews, and salary negotiations, particularly within IT, finance, government, and technical sectors.

Experience:

Employer: Cyberminds Inc.

Role: US IT Recruiter

• 3 Years of experience as US staffing IT. Highly effective in utilizing best practices in recruiting, sourcing candidates through conventional means.

Duration: April 2022 – Present

Duration: July 2018 - Apri 2022

- Strong knowledge of recruiting and hiring processes including sourcing, interviewing, reference checking, tracking, salary negotiations, and closing.
- Done technical interviews, and co-coordinating online skills tests, scheduling phone interviews with the Client and managing the internal database for my consultants or candidates.
- Worked on State client requirement with CAI and HBITS vendors for State of NY and other States client role. (State of GA, Iowa, Idaho and Indiana).
- Worked with Tier 1 Vendors also like Kforce, TEKsystems, Eliassen Group, Judge Group, IDR and Randstad, for their Client in Domains like BFSI, Healthcare, and Automobile.
- Understanding of terms US citizen/GC/EAD/H1B and other visa status as well as Tax Terms 1099/C2C/CTH/W2 etc.
- Have excellent Technical, inter-personal and communication skills.
- Extensive expertise in handling recruitment, and post recruitment activities which includes hiring right candidate, conducting joining formalities and induction.

Tools: Google Sheets, ATS, Ceipal, iLabor360, Vector VMS, Job Diva, MS-Word, MS-Excel, MS Teams, etc.

Conduent, Inc./Continumm Global Solution

Role: Sr. Transaction Processor

- Analyze transcribe audio, extract relevant information, and route calls to the correct department involves several steps and technologies.
- Analyze the transcribed text to extract relevant information. This may include key words, phrases, or patterns that indicate the purpose or topic of the call.
- Implement a decision-making algorithm to determine the correct department based on the extracted information. This could be a rule-based system, a machine learning model, or a combination of both.
- Once the correct department is identified, implement a routing mechanism to direct the call to the appropriate destination. This might involve integrating with a telephony system or a customer relationship management (CRM) system.
- If the computer isn't very sure or makes a mistake, send the call to a real person to help out.

Abhilash Shrivas

Phone: 6261088715 Email: Abhilashcyberminds@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/abhilash-shrivas-9196ba235/

Tools: MS –Excel, Slack, MS-Words etc.

Employer: Teleperfomance, Indore Duration: Aug 2017 - May 2018

Role: Customer support Executive (PhonePe)

- Used the Avaya/Freshdesk platform to interact with customers via inbound, outbound, and Email requests regarding their orders and complaints.
- Interpreted customer concerns and shared accurate information in an empathetic way.
- Resolved customer queries through internal tools and process knowledge.
- Being a senior member, helped the team to bring up new updates and process changes in motion.
- Connected with multiple teams to resolve and escalate customer concerns.
- Performed SME duties and helped new joiners with process support and helped them meet the KPIs in different situations.
- Maintained customer satisfaction, average handling time, chat quality and other key major KPIs.

Tools: Avaya, MS office, Client internal tools CS Consle, Freshdesk.

Hexaware Technologies, Nagpur

Role: Data Quality Assurance executive

 Manage the day-to-day Data Quality administration function, operational performance reporting, tracking requests.

Duration: Mar 2017 -Sep 2017

- Work with the team to ensure continuous process improvement
- Assist Team lead in preparing detailed metrics packs showing data quality information for distribution to management
- Responsible for managing performance of a team of Data Quality Specialists by setting clear goals, objectives and quality of work.

Education:

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology from RTM Nagpur University - 2017

Certification:

- Microsoft Power Platform Fundamentals Training/Preparing
- Google Associate Cloud Engineer Certification –Nov 2024.
- Beeline Platform Contingent Staffing Level I Certification from Beeline Feb 2024
- Naukri Maestro Recruiter Program from Naukri.com in Dec 2023
- Six Sigma White Belt Certification 2024